the internet is littered with a ton of
different day trading strategy setups
and systems and I'm not saying that some
of them aren't profitable but if I had
to start over from scratch if I was a
beginner or someone struggling to make
money from day trading then the strategy
I'm gonna be sharing with you today is
exactly where I would start so in this
video I'm going to be breaking this
entire strategy Down based on a set of
rules you can use like a checklist to
check off every time you're about to
place a trade in your own day trading
and this strategy is the exact strategy
I used to get involved here on the
Canada Yen the trade you see on the
screen down here on the 15 minute chart
so I'm going to talk you through this
trade teach you the strategy and by the
end of this video you're going to have a
full rules-based day trading strategy
that is perfect for beginner or
struggling Traders so if that sounds
good go ahead and click that like button
for me go and subscribe if you're new to
the channel hit that notification Bell
and I'll be right back after the intro
and disclaimer
foreign
[Music]
I'm glad you stuck around through the
intro and disclaimer you're gonna be
happy that you did if you're brand new
to the channel my name is Steven I've
been trading for over a decade and on
this channel I try my best to give you
every trick tip and strategy that I've
learned through the past decade of my
own trading experience in order to help
you speed up your journey to profitable
trading so with that said let's take a
look at this strategy in this Canada Yen
trade this specific strategy uses two
different time frames and one of these
time frames is going to be used for
something very specific it's going to be
used to tell me if I'm going to be
buying or selling it's also going to be
used to tell me where I'm going to be
buying and selling let me explain more
about that by taking a look at the
charts as you can see here on the Canada
Yen I have plotted this blue line this
blue line is the 50 EMA so the first
thing I want to see with this strategy
is that price is trending above the 50
EMA what that means is that price is
consistently making higher highs
higher lows higher highs higher lows and
higher highs here on the Canada Yen and
anytime I'm using this strategy this has
to be happening above the 50 EMA and a
lot of people get confused by markets
that start to do something like this if
prices instead of making higher highs
and higher lows in a very clear way like
they are here on the Canada Yen if they
were doing something like this
I would just not trade so to keep this
really simple and to keep you from
having to deal with do I need to trade
or not based on if the market is
trending or consolidating if it's not an
extremely clear Trend meaning if you
can't clearly see prices making higher
highs and higher lows then I just simply
don't trade at that time and I'll wait
for Trend to become clear in this case
it was a bad trade I was looking for an
uptrend looking for prices to be making
higher highs and higher lows at the
point
that I see that prices are in fact
making higher highs and higher lows than
I know I'm going to be looking for buy
trades after I know I'm looking for bad
trades that's step one which direction
do I want to trade the next step is
where where am I looking for those buy
trades and for this specific strategy
it's only one place that's why this
strategy is so good if you're a beginner
or a struggling Trader with your day
trading is because we're looking for one
place to place a buy or sell trade
saying place that many times felt
awkward but right here at the previous
high that was just broken is the area
I'm looking for price to pull back to in
order to place possible by trades so we
have the direction which is up I want to
be buying this Market because why
because we are in an uptrend prices are
making higher odds and higher lows and
we now have the where which is what or
where the where is the previous level of
resistance that's likely to become
support in an uptrend so now that I've
broken that down kind of on a whiteboard
let's go to the actual trade itself here
on the Canada Yen so right here in
Market replay mode based on the drawing
I just did what can you see happening
do we have a valid uptrend well our
prices consistently making higher highs
and higher lows yes they are is it clear
high or high high or low now we just
made a higher high after I see this
higher hot made my next step is going to
be to point out the previous level of
resistance in a zone that looks
something like that once I have this
level pointed out I know I'm in buy mode
because we're in an uptrend and now I
know where I want to be a buyer it is in
this Zone we just pointed out in Gray so
the next step here is to wait for price
to pull back to this gray Zone and then
I'm going to be dropping down to a day
trading time frame in order to place my
entry so earlier I said I used two
different time frames for this strategy
when I'm day trading I'm always looking
for Trend meaning what direction do I
want to go do I want to be a buyer or a
seller so I look for Trend on the four
hour chart and I also look for the
structure level or the where do I want
to buy on the four hour chart after I
have these two things pointed out I wait
on this time frame for prices to get
into that zone then I drop down to my
day trading time frame which is the 15
minute chart so if we push the candles
forward here just a bit you can see that
we now have gotten into our buy zone so
at the moment I get into that buy zone
I'm dropping down to a 15 minute chart
this is the 15 minute chart I forgot to
mention this during the recording and
here we are a day later I'm editing this
video but I wanted to let you know you
can also use this on even lower time
frames by looking for Trend and
structure on the one hour and looking
for your trades on a five minute chart
so keep that in mind moving forward now
on the 15 minute chart I'm looking for
two very specific chart patterns using
this strategy I am either looking for a
double bottom in this zone or I'm
looking for a head and shoulders pattern
in this Zone shoulder neckline head
second shoulder push higher those are
the only two ways I'm going to be
entering a trade with this strategy once
the other conditions I just said are met
so here on the 15 minute chart let's
push price forward and see what we get
right here we get a double bottom but
what I'm going to be waiting on is not
just the double bottom not just the head
and shoulders pattern I want to see a
break of the neckline I want to see a
breakout showing me that buying pressure
is going to continue past the double
bottom so with that being the case and
that being my actual entry I have no
reason to enter yet as we push forward I
still do not have a reason to enter the
trade because we have no close above the
neckline of this double bottom so we
continue waiting to see what price does
we continue waiting for a close above
our actual neckline on this double
bottom which eventually turns into a
triple bottom and eventually does in
fact break above the neckline of our
double bottom so with this being the
case we finally get a close above the
neckline of this double bottom that is
my actual entry so after all the other
things are met that I'm looking for on
the four hour chart we have price in an
uptrend making new higher lows and
higher highs we have the previous level
of resistance that should turn into
support that price has now pulled back
to I've now dropped down to the 15
minute chart and I'm looking for what
I'm looking for a double bottom or a
head and shoulders pattern with the
break of a neckline
for confirmation once I get that that is
when I'm actually going to be pressing
the buy button so that's when I decided
to actually place this specific trade
and we'll jump out to the four hour for
now hit the play button as you can see
since doing so prices have in fact
pushed higher and the specific trade is
currently at about a 2.1 to 1 reward to
risk ratio just using this very simple
strategy now
you can say I wait for trend for
structure and for chart patterns to
trade but if you do that you're probably
going to be very inconsistent in your
trading which is why it's important to
create a framework that is rules for the
specific strategy which is what I'm
going to show you now I do this through
a process I call c-e-s-t it's an acronym
that if you've been a part of the
channel for a while you know all too
well
c-e-s-t stands for conditions entries
stops and targets so for this strategy
what would the conditions be the
conditions would be four hour chart it's
in an uptrend
and is pulled back to the previous
resistance that was broken in this
uptrend those are the only conditions
I'm looking for for this strategy what
would be the entry the entry for this
strategy would be we're in our Zone and
price either makes a double bottom and
breaks above the neckline or makes a
head and shoulders pattern and breaks
above the neckline of that head and
shoulders pattern the next thing we have
to do is establish rules for our stops
and Targets in order to be consistent
for me the stop loss goes below the zone
that I created and I personally just
manage my position on a lower time frame
which is exactly what I'm doing now and
those are the rules for a bullish
version of this strategy just so you can
see that I not only trade this way
myself I also sent this trade out to all
the members of the TTC 4X University you
can see that on the left side of your
screen and again that's something
included in the TDC Forex University if
you're interested in learning more about
that it'll be the top Link in the
description or you can go to
www.thetradingchannel.com otherwise what
I want to do now is move on and show you
a bearish version of this strategy the
bearish version of this strategy is the
same exact thing just flipped upside
down let's take a look right now on the
Whiteboard so instead of being in an
uptrend let's say this is our 50 EMA we
want to see prices making new lower lows
and lower highs now below the 50 EMA
when that starts to happen instead of
looking at a previous resistance we're
actually going to be looking at the
previous support level that price has
just broken we're gonna be waiting for
price to get back up to that level we're
gonna be dropping down then to lower
time frames to look for either double
tops or a head and shoulders pattern and
the entry will be the break of the
neckline of the double top or the head
and shoulders pattern let's take a look
at an example of this on the charts here
we have the pound Yen prices are pushing
below the 50 EMA are they also creating
new lower highs and lower lows well it's
pretty clear to see that we have a high
here pushing to a low a lower high a
lower low an equal high and now a lower
low this would be a good trending Market
to the downside meaning I'm looking for
sell trades that's the direction I want
to look for trading opportunities in now
because of the fact that we're below the
50 EMA creating lower highs and lower
lows in a downtrend the next step is to
point out the area that I see for a
possible trade that area is always going
to be the recent level of support that
was broken in this case we have this
move here back up back down previous
level of support that was broken is
right here already have that zone drawn
in for you what's the next steps well
now we have the conditions met right the
conditions were four hours shows me
Trend in this case it's a downtrend and
four hour shows me an area of structure
like we have here that I'm going to be
trading in the next thing we wait for is
to pull back up to this area then we
take a look at entries let's hit play
and see when we actually get into our
Zone we are now in our zone so let's
take a look now on a lower time frame so
as you can see here we've come into our
Zone starting all the way back here but
have we had a double top or a head and
shoulder pattern that broke below the
neckline of that double top or head and
shoulder pattern well no we have not we
get this like double top right here but
the neckline would be way down here we
get another double top here here almost
like a triple top but in that case we
would need this level to be broken we
have not gotten any type of double top
yet that's broken the neckline or a head
and shoulders pattern that has broken a
neckline so let's keep pushing price
forward and see if we actually get one
here we have another
double top okay so now we're looking
right here this is our double top we
have one top here followed by our second
top all we need is a break below this
neckline and we have a valid trade so
let's push the market forward one more
time and there we go this would be a
valid trade and the way I would be
looking to trade this is by placing a
stop loss depending on if the price the
top of the double top is close to or far
away from the top of my zone if it's
super far away let's say we get a double
top way down here I'll do it over here
way down here I wouldn't be putting my
stop balls all the way above my zone I
would just go one ATR or 10 20 Pips five
Pips whatever you want to do I would
just go above that double top if it
happened super low in the zone like this
but for this case this double top
happened very high in the zone so with
that being the case I'm just going to
put my stop loss right above the zone
I'm gonna aim for something like a two
to one and be wary of my levels of
structure I see this level here as a
pretty major little zone so what I'm
going to do is go in between that zone
and that's going to be my target so
there you go the trade is set up we have
all of our conditions met let's hit play
and see how it worked out
oh no we had a losing trade which is a
great segue into the next part of the
video I wish that I could tell you that
this strategy would win a hundred
percent of the time trust me if it would
win 100 of the time I would have way
more money in my trading account right
now and I wish I could tell you that
there was any strategy out there that
could win 100 of the time but that's
just not the case winning 100 of the
time while trading is not possible what
that means is that you will have losses
no matter what strategy you're trading
no matter how good you get a trading
you're never gonna know exactly what the
Market's going to do back whenever I
first started trading for some reason I
truly believed that the reason
professional traders made money is
because they knew exactly what price was
going to do and every trade they place
they just won those trades but
throughout my trading career I learned
that that's not the case at all the
truth is that we are trading as
professional Traders whenever you be
become a professional Trader you will be
trading based on a statistic advantage
that plays out over a large sample size
of Trades so it's not about knowing
exactly what the Market's going to do
it's about trading a proven rules-based
system that's proven to be profitable
over a large sample size of Trades and
that you know will create profits if you
do it over and over again even though it
will have some losses in between so now
that you know that losses are a part of
trading and I'm sure that if you've ever
experienced a loss you know that it can
be somewhat emotional it can make you
want to switch strategies it can make
you want to shrink your target up on the
next trade or push your stop loss higher
and higher or lower lower to keep from
losing money you get really emotional
during losses and that's completely
normal but what we have to do as Traders
is find a way to mitigate those emotions
during losses so since you know that
losses are a part of trading what are
some ways we can mitigate those emotions
well the first one is really simple the
first one this is what I do all the
students in the university is risk
management the more money you are
risking on each trade the more emotional
you're going to be and look
you may have a day in the future once
you're already a professional Trader you
understand everything there is to know
about trading you have your whole
trading plan set up you may choose to
risk a pretty high amount because you're
good at that point and you'll know when
that's the case you'll know when you're
good at trading but until that gets here
until you become good at trading your
point in trading
is not to try to gain as much money as
you can by risking 10 percent or more of
your account
if you do that you will blow your
account and the reason this doesn't work
when you're a beginner or a struggling
Trader is because you're not good at
trading yet so while you're in the
beginner slash struggling Trader phase
of your trading career your risk
management needs to be much much lower
so that you mitigate the emotions you
have when you have losses and you lose
money slower risk management the amount
we risk on each trade can help us to
gain more over a certain period of time
but it can also cause us to lose more
over a certain period of time so if
you're a beginner or someone just
starting out or even someone who has
just become profitable then risking a
ton of your account on every trade is
more than likely going to end and you
blowing that account or pushing that
account to such a negative balance that
you can't control your emotions any
longer so the way we handle those
emotions that we have whenever we're
losing trades is by having a good risk
management plan the second way we do
this is to have more confidence more
faith in the system strategy or
strategies that we are trading in the
way we gain more faith in those systems
is through the process of back testing
back testing is nothing more than taking
the rules like you just learned in this
video the CEST rules you take those
rules you look back in historic data
throughout the past 100 trades or more
and you ask yourself how many times did
It win versus lose when it won what was
my reward to risk ratio and with these
two numbers you can figure out if a
strategy is likely to be profitable in
the future the only strategies you
should be trading are strategies likely
to be profitable in the future and the
way that we determine if something's
likely to be profitable in the future is
through back testing and this back
testing process also gives us an
incredible amount of confidence that
helps us deal with drawdowns losing
trades and helps us handle our emotions
and have a better trading mindset now
mastering a strategy or strategies that
makes money over time mastering your
risk management and mastering your
trading mindset or trading psychology is
something that can be really difficult
on your own and for that reason I'm
looking for 500 new or struggling
traders to Mentor throughout the rest of
this year on their journey to profitable
trading inside of the TDC Forex
University if you want to learn more
details about that University all you
have to do is click the top Link in the
description or go to
www.thetradingchannel.com it obviously
comes with a full University style
course it comes with the pro trade
report every Monday talking about the
zones I'm actually looking to trade in
it comes with three to five Trading
alerts per week of Trades I'm actually
taking based on the strategies you're
learning in the course and it comes with
priority email meaning that you will
have contact with me directly for any
trading related questions that you may
have on top of all that it also has a
30-day money-back guarantee so if you'd
like to check out the details of that
again top Link in the description or go
to www dot the trade example.com if not
completely fine too I wish you all the
luck in your future trades and I'll talk
to you in the next video